ReadMe 

Permutation testing for within-subject GFP was carried out as follows: 

(1) Collect the trials of two experimental conditions/two different stimulus types in a single set 

(2) Random partition: randomly draw as many trials from this combined data set as there were trials in condition 1/stimulus type 1 and place those trials in subset 1. Place the remaining trials in subset 2. 

(3) Calculate the test statistic (i.e., here, t-test is used) on this random partition. 

(4) Repeat steps 2 and 3 a large number of times and construct a histogram of the test statistic. This number is called permutation number. Although, the number of permutation can be made with a group-average ERP based on N participants is 2^N, it has been shown that 1,000-5,000 permutation is sufficient (Manly, 1991). Hence, a 5,000 permutation number was used in all the tests. 

(5) This histogram of the test statistic was used to determine the likihood of the statistic observed in the actual experiment. 

(6) This procedure was then repeated for each time point. 


Many, BF. (1991). Randomization, bootstrap and Monte Carlo methods in biology. London, UK: Chapman & Hall. 